1435 Bedford St, Stamford, CT 06905 | 321-312-9967 | jigarOcp@gmail.com | Medium | Linkedin

## **DevOps Engineer**

### **Summary**

I have over 9 years of experience in Software Engineering. I started my careen in 2013 as a Junior Software Engineer. Eventually, got more interested towards tools like Jenkins, OpenStack, Kubernetes and now Amazon Web Services and built profile for a DevOps engineer. I am a motivated, quick learner and a problem solver.

**Jenkins** 

Java/Python

Oracle/Elasticsearch

Git & Gerrit

Linux

Kafka Confluent

### **Skills**

Kubernetes

OpenStack, AWS

Ansible

•	Docker	<ul> <li>RESTful API</li> </ul>	•	Apache Ant/Maven
Education & Experience				
•	Certified Kubernetes Applic Developer	cation		Sep 2021
0	<b>Interactive Brokers</b>			Since Nov 2017
•	<b>AWS Certified Solution Architect</b>			Aug 2017
•	<b>Thesis</b> The effects of virtualization in Database benchmarking			May 2017
•	Florida Institute of Technology, FL Master of Computer Science			Aug 2015-May 2017 GPA 3.75/4.0
0	Elitecore Technologies Pvt L	Ltd		Feb 2013-Aug 2015
•	Oracle Certified Java Programmer			Dec 2013
•	LDRP ITR, Gandhinagar, In Bachelor of Computer Engine			May 2009-May 2013 CGPA 7.26/10

### **Work Experience**

#### **Interactive Brokers**

DevOps Engineer Since Nov 2017

- Managed 8000+ git repositories using Gerrit and permissions
- Setup multi-node Kafka cluster and defined a strong Disaster Recovery plan
- Maintain & upgrade Jenkins, Kafka, Gerrit (reduced upgrade time from several weeks to a day by setting up test environment)
- Integrated WhiteSource Security management tool with Jenkins
- Assisted to onboard Sonatype Nexus and ElasticCo
- Wrote Ansible roles to setup ELK clusters
- Increased availability of Gerrit by setting up Disaster Recovery
- Added features to the in-house tool which interfaces with Gerrit, Jenkins, and Git
- Wrote groovy scripts and python scripts to update Jenkins jobs in bulk
- Created documents to onboard users with Ansible/Kafka/Gerrit

#### **Novatio Technologies**

RPA Developer

Aug 2017 – Nov 2017

- Setup RPA training environment on AWS
- Reduced the cost of AWS environment by 40% by adapting Centralized RDS and converting AWS workspaces to small VM
- Wrote RPA automation to automate bill payment and transferring data from Oracle E-business suite to Salesforce

#### **Harris Institute for Assured Information**

Research Assistant

Feb 2016 – May 2017

- Wrote Ansible script to implement PXE services on remote machines to install ubuntu 14.
- Integrated Sensu with VINE to monitor virtual machines.
- Used Git to maintain Ansible Roles and to commit the development requirements.
- Created automated process to perform code analysis using Jenkins and shell scripts.
- Utilized OpenStack Neutron API to create and manage a virtual network for Virtual Infrastructure Network Emulator (VINE) product.
- Defined hierarchical user-data namely VINE specific, testbed specific, and Virtual Machine (VM) specific usage for the Virtual Machine.
- Created service network per testbed to increase the manageability of VMs.
- Implemented import/export functionality to create an identical environment across different VINE instances.
- Migrated the codebase from OpenStack 2.0.4 to OpenStack 3.0.

• Published thesis on "The Effects of Virtualization on Database Benchmarking".

#### Elitecore Technologies Pvt Ltd, India

Junior Software Engineer

Aug 2013 – Aug 2015

- Implemented Direct Debit payment feature using various technologies such as EJB, JPA, and ZK.
- Wrote tables, queries, procedures, schedulers, and triggers to transfer data from the production database to Operational Data Store.
- Created business reports such as daily/monthly/yearly payment reports, mode-wise payment reports.
- Reduced the task of managing the server by writing shell scripts to perform various tasks such as fetching the latest code, compiling the code, and deploying deliverables on the server and integrated them with Jenkins.
- Automated the process of generating flush scripts to remove the test data from the database.
- Identified the areas of improvement by performing load testing using Apache JMeter.
- Integrated JRebel with the codebase and performed live deployment on the JBoss server which reduces the compilation and deployment time by 20%.
- Used JIRA to test and track the Issues and Bugs and for the Project Management.

#### Elitecore Technologies Pvt Ltd, India

Software Engineering Intern

Feb 2013 – Aug 2013

- Integrated code analysis tools such as FindBugs and Sonar.
- Utilized delegate and singleton design patterns to develop code.
- Migrated code from JDBC to JPA and designed GUI in ZK OSS.
- Wrote Ant build scripts to compile the java code, deploy the application on the JBoss server, and perform code analysis.
- Used JBoss application server to test and deploy the application.
- Managed the database and server to identify and resolve inter-module problems.

#### Co-curricular Activities

- Medium https://medium.com/@jigarr
- o Github https://github.com/JigarProjects
- Credly https://www.credly.com/users/jigarkumar-rathod/badges#



The Cloud Native Computing Foundation hereby certifies that

# Jigarkumar Rathod

has successfully completed the program requirements to be recognized as a

# **Certified Kubernetes Application Developer**

PRIYANKA SHAMMA, GENERAL MANAGER CLOUD NATIVE COMPUTING FOUNDATION September 16, 2021

DATE OF COMPLETION

LF-maqa9wj692

CERTIFICATE ID NUMBER

To verify the status of this Certificate, please visit http://training.linuxfoundation.org/certification/verify



# Jigarkumar Rathod

has successfully completed the AWS Certification requirements and has achieved their:

# AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate

Issue Date August 04, 2017

Expiration Date August 04, 2019 Wannen Joresgan

Maureen Lonergan Director, Training and Certification

Validation Number 50X1EYT1CM1414W0 Validate at: http://aws.amazon.com/verification

